HOSSEIN SHARIFINIA

FRONT-END Developer

LinkedIn | □ +98-9308242540 | M hosein.sharifinia@gmail.com | O GitHub

About Me

I'm a frontend developer with +5 years of experience designing and implementing web applications in production environments. Specialize in Javascript and have a deep understanding of its concepts and edge cases. Currently, working on a platform that serves over 5 million users (app, website, PWA). My skills and expertise enable me to create responsive, user-friendly web applications that meet the highest quality and performance standards.

Skills

- JavaScript | TypeScript | React is | Next.is | Nodeis | Nest.is | Express is
- Redux | Redux toolkit | Redux Saga | Redux Thunk | React Router | React-Query | React-hook-form | MaterialUI |
 Ant-Design | Formik | Next-PWA | Framer motion | Socket.io
- Webpack | Babel | GraphQL | Git | Web Vitals | Jest | Unit Testing | React Testing Library | Prettier | Eslint | Storybook
- CSS | Sass | Bootstrap | Post Css | Tailwind | JSS | Purge CSS | Emotion
- CI/CD | Docker | GitlabCi | Github Action
- Jira | Azure
- Design Patterns | System Design | Mentoring

Experience ___

Senior Frontend Developer

Tehran Internet (780)

Tehran/Iran

Nov 2021 - Present

- Contributed to the successful completion of a complete redesign of an existing web application, transitioning it to modern technologies, including **React**, **TypeScript**, and **Next.js**.
- Implemented project linters (prettier, committint, eslint, husky) to improve code consistency and reduce conflicts among team members.
- Enforced OpenAPI typescript to convert schemas to TypeScript types, reducing server response type costs.
- Boosted team productivity and collaboration by regularly sharing knowledge on emerging tech with 15+ developers.
- Increased unit/integration test coverage using Jest & React-testing-library.
- Improved web vitals (LCP, FID, CLS) using Lighthouse & CRUX API, resulting in 50% faster page loads, 40% fewer bounces, and higher engagement/satisfaction.

Tech: Javascript, React, Typescript, Next.js, React-query, Framer motion, React-hook-form, Next-PWA, Firebase

Frontend Developer (remote)

RealPars

Amsterdam/Netherland Apr 2020 - Nov 2021

- Reduced build size by code splitting and replacing legacy redux-thunk with react-query for server state.
- Launched dashboard by migrating 100% legacy components to new ones using React hooks.
- Improved project structure by configuring MonoRepo and reducing dependencies by 40%.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to identify and remove user impediments to site interaction.
- Developed UI component documentation with **Storybook**, established development guidelines, and enhanced efficiency and consistency in the UI component development process.

Tech: Javascript, React, Next.js, Lerna, Typescript, StoryBook, Redux toolkit, AntDesign, Emotion | Socket.io

- Built an E-commerce site using React and Redux, achieving 95% unit test code coverage for optimal user experience.
- Streamlined website performance up to 60% by analyzing designs and refining quick loading and user accessibility.
- Coded logistics and warehouse dashboard using React, Typescript, and Google Charts for a rich visual summary of daily user purchase patterns.
- Gained daily traffic from 10k to 40k by redesigning existing websites to improve user experience.

Tech: Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, Redux-thunk, React-hook-form, ApexChart.js, Material-UI | GSAP

Frontend Developer

Farabi Accelerator

Tehran/Iran

Dec 2017 - Nov 2018

- Reduced downtime by 15% through a performance improvement process.
- Developed a vanilla JavaScript library for user interaction detection and ad display.
- Enhanced site ranking through SEO strategy and an intuitive interface.
- Optimized dashboard code base scalability and readability by migrating complex states to a single Redux store.

tech: Javascript, React, Redux, Redux-Saga, Axios, Bootstrap, Scss, Jest, Enzyme, Gatsby.js

Education			
Bachelor of engineering	Azad University	Iran. Rasht	2013 - 2016